ANDREW KAN

Full Stack Software Engineer

Andrewkn09@gmail.com | North Wales, Pennsylvania | (917) 330-7072 github.com/andrewk09 | linkedin.com/in/andrew-kn | andrewkan.me

SUMMARY

Dependable Software Engineer with 3 years of hands-on development experience in object-oriented programming, design, implementation, and debugging code. Effective communicator capable of taking requirements and transforming them into results. Currently seeking to build amazing software within a collaborative organization

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, Semantic HTML, CSS, SQL

Front-End: React, Redux, Next.js, jQuery

Back-End: Node.js, Express, RESTful APIs, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Redis

Deployment: Amazon Web Services, Heroku, Docker, Oracle Cloud

Tools: Git, npm, Webpack, ESLint, Jest, Socket.io

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Software Engineer

Jul 2020 - Feb 2023

SPJ Solutions | Remote

- Developed Virtual Machine migration feature using **React** and **Node.js** to handle various migration scenarios, successfully migrating thousands of virtual machines with 99.99% uptime.
- Built **RESTful APIs** and database structures utilizing **Node**, **Express** and **PostgreSQL** to support frontend functionality, integrating with various data sources and complex **third-party APIs**.
- Designed and implemented a reusable Task Manager UI in React to modularize automation processes and reduce redeployment times by 60% in cases of environmental issues.
- Significantly enhanced customer experience through collaboration with a cross-functional agile team of networking consultants, effectively troubleshooting issues and developing features tailored to meet diverse customer requirements.
- Pioneered effort to introduce additional unit testing using Jest, React Testing Library, and
 TeamCity to ensure code quality which resulted in additional bugs being discovered and fixed.
- Reviewed PRs and provided constructive feedback to help improve code quality and maintainability.

Software Engineering Immersive Resident

Aug 2019 - Nov 2019

Galvanize | New York, NY

- Mentored students in JavaScript fundamentals, data structures, and front/back-end technologies resulting in 100% students passing the midterm.
- Utilized Agile Methodology to meet team development goals.
- Evaluated the technical abilities of prospective students with live coding interviews.

APPLICATIONS

Greenfield Shopping Portal

Technologies: React, Redux, React-Router, Material-UI, AWS EC2

Project Description:

Developed an **e-commerce web application** enabling users to browse a highly **responsive web page** featuring an image gallery, questions and answers, and ratings and reviews section.

- Leveraged Redux for efficient state management, ensuring smooth data flow and centralized control over global data.
- Adhered to design specifications for the reviews component, delivering a highly responsive and visually appealing user interface.
- Collaborated with a team of 3 developers, conducting daily code reviews and using Git's feature branch workflow to meet project goals.
- Integrated with RESTful API, manipulating complex data for client-side rendering.

Discord Music Bot

Technologies: Node.js, Discord.js, Sapphire Framework, Docker, PostgreSQL, Oracle Cloud **Project Description**:

Developed a custom Discord Music Bot capable of seamlessly streaming music from popular platforms including Spotify, YouTube, and SoundCloud. The bot stands out by its ability to handle playlists with a capacity of over 100 songs, surpassing the limitations of most other music bots.

- Implemented essential music playback commands, including search, skip, and loop, providing users with an enjoyable listening experience.
- Utilized Docker for efficient containerization and deployed the bot to Oracle Cloud, ensuring 24/7 availability and high-quality music streaming.
- Enabled users to manage music playback by utilizing the Sapphire framework to create custom bot commands
- Successfully integrated with Spotify API, expanding the bot's music library and offering users access to a diverse selection of tracks.

EDUCATION:

Hack Reactor | Advanced Software Engineering Immersive | New York, NY **University at Buffalo** | B.S. in Biological Sciences | Buffalo, NY

Jun 2019 - Aug 2019 Sep 2014 - May 2018